A Guide to the New Virginia Review Archives, 1978-1987
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
New Virginia Review Archives, 1978-1987
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 179
3 linear feet.
New Virginia Review Archives
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for use without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection is on deposit from the New Virginia Review.
Biographical/Historical Information
New Virginia Review, Inc. is a non-profit, statewide literary organization dedicated to the cultivation and development of informed audiences for literature throughout the state, and to the creation of new opportunities for writers to present their works to the public. It has published six volumes of an annual journal containing prose and poetry by authors associated with Virginia and the South. It is supported by the Virginia Commission for the Arts, the National Endowment for the Arts, and public and private contributions
Scope and Content Information
The collection consists of manuscripts submitted for the New Virginia Review, Volumes I and V; correspondence between contributors and editors; proofs representing various stages of the production process; and a number of taped readings and lectures. Included in the collection are a number of journals and books which have been marked and assimilated into the regular Special Collections small press and poetry collections.
Arrangement
Arrangement
Materials arranged by series and chronologically therein.
Organization
The collection has been augmented by the following materials donated by Mrs. Betty Scott in January 1994: materials added receipt for donation, 2 copies of New Virginia Review March 1982, copies of membership application cards and the New Virginia Review Fact Sheet.
Series I--NVR Papers (1978-1987)
Series II--Audio Tapes
Series III--Oversized Material (1983-1986)
Contents List
- NVR Papers 1978-1987
  - Biographies of Contributors 1985-1986 (Box-folder 1.1)
  - Correspondence: Contributors 1978 (Box-folder 1.2)
  - Correspondence: Small Press 1979-1981 (Box-folder 1.3)
  - Miscellaneous Publications 1978-1984 (Box-folder 1.4)
  - New Virginia Association for the Arts 1977-1978 (Box-folder 1.5)
  - Applications for Fellowship Program 1981 (Box-folder 1.5a)
  - Poems submitted by Leon Stokesbury for Fellowship Program (Box-folder 1.5b)
  - NVR Volume I: Manuscripts/Correspondence 1978 (Box-folder 1.6)
  - NVR, Volume I: Manuscripts/Correspondence 1978 (Box-folder 1.7)
  - NVR, Volume I: Production Notes 1978 (Box-folder 2.1)
  - NVR, Volume I: Proofs 1978 (Box-folder 2.2)
  - NVR, Volume I: Proofs 1978 (Box-folder 2.3)
  - NVR, Volume I: Proofs 1978 (Box-folder 2.4)
  - NVR, Volume III: Proofs 1984 (Box-folder 3.1)
  - NVR, Volume III: Proofs 1984 (Box-folder 3.2)
  - NVR, Volume III: Typed Manuscripts 1984 (Box-folder 3.3)
  - NVR, Volume III: Typed Manuscripts 1984 (Box-folder 3.4)
  - NVR, Volume III: Typed Manuscripts (Poetry) 1984 (Box-folder 3.5)
  - NVR, Volume III: Typed Manuscripts (Fiction) 1984 (Box-folder 3.6)
  - NVR, Volume V: Proofs 1987 (Box-folder 3.7)
  - Folders 1-4 NVR, Volume V: Typed Manuscripts 1987 (Box 4)
  - Folders 1-4, NVR, Volume V: Typed Manuscripts 1987 (Box 5)
  - NVR, Volume V: Typed Manuscripts 1987 (Box-folder 6.1)
  - NVR, Volume V: Typed Manuscripts 1987 (Box-folder 6.2)
  - Correspondence/Manuscripts 1985-1986 (Box-folder 6.3)
  - Correspondence/Manuscripts 1985-1986 (Box-folder 6.4)
  - Correspondence/Manuscripts 1985-1986 (Box-folder 6.5)
  - Correspondence 1987-1988 (Box-folder 6.6)
- Audio Tapes
  - Brock Evans (Box 7)
  - Ursula Molinero (Box 7)
  - Mignon Anderson (Box 7)
  - Derek Walcott (Box 7)
  - Stokesbury (Box 7)
  - White/Rarber/Molinero Panel (Box 7)
  - June Jordan and Bernice Reagon (Box 7)
  - Jones (Box 7)
  - White/Molinero (Box 7)
  - Bensko (Box 7)
  - Ardizzone (Box 7)
  - Betsy Sholl (Box 7)
- Oversized Material
  - Photographic Plate for NVR Volume IV 1986, oversized
  - Poster for Book and Author Tour 1983, oversized